hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation
playlist now continuing with our test
automation obstacle topic let's look at
our next obstacle which is called the
last row now in this particular obstacle
we need to uh verify that the last row
in the table displays an order value and
then we need to take this value and put
it on the text field okay so for example
if this is the table then we need to
grab this particular value here and then
we need to enter it right here and then
the obstacle will be completed now take
note that this table is dynamically
getting changed so this value won't be
constant neither the number of rows will
be constant
right so this is very similar to the
last obstacle where we found uh the
number of rows which are present in a
particular table and then entered it
into a text field here we need to uh
verify and grab the last value of uh
this particular table okay so let's see
how we can do this in tosa so coming
back to our tosa workpace uh let's go to
our module section and here we will go
to obstacle
and here we will be adding a new module
right so let's scan the
application and here we'll be adding uh
two elements one is the table itself and
then the text box okay so these are uh
the two elements which we want and then
let's save it and let's close it
it okay so I'm going to rename the
module
first okay and then uh we are going to
create a new test case under our
obstacles
folder uh with the same test case name
which is the obstacle number okay and
then we are going to select our module
so let's grab the module and let's add
it here and now uh we have got a table
and a text box okay so right now in this
table you can see uh the row element and
the column element now there are two uh
ways you can do this okay so we need to
select the last row of this particular
table no matter how many rows are there
we always want to select the last row
right so for this uh what we can do we
can use two types of um Elements which
are present here uh one is the this last
dollar okay so when you select this
dollar last then it will always select
the last row of this particular table
okay so whatever value it will contain
you can find it using this particular
row so once this row is selected then uh
we just need to select the particular
cell okay and uh we know that it is in
the value colum okay so what I can do I
can um go here and I can check that uh
in the value column I have got this
particular value right so this is what I
want to grab okay so here uh instead of
verification what I can do I can buffer
this particular value okay and then um I
can also put something here called bore
Val okay so this is my buffer name where
this particular value will be stored
okay and once this is stored then um I
can just go ahead and enter it into the
text box okay so I can use the buffer so
bore
Val okay and then um it will be entered
into this particular text box okay so
I'll show you the other way as well uh
let's first run this and let's check
whether it is working or not okay so
I'll mark this as completed and then I
am going to run
this
okay so as you can see uh it grabbed
that uh particular value and it entered
it into the text box okay now the other
way around is uh instead of dollar last
we can also use uh the last content row
okay so dollar last content row so this
will also select the last row so you can
use any of these two elements which are
already part of the table row element
element type okay so now if I go ahead
and run this in scratchbook
again it will exactly do the same
thing okay so this is how you can uh
basically uh play around with uh
different row elements so especially for
first and last row there is already a
option which is present for the row
element you can see dollar one is always
the first row then dollar n you can
enter any particular row number and then
uh the last uh the last content row
would always um contain the last row and
then you can also put uh you can also
verify the headers or you can also
verify whether uh it is the first empty
row okay so these are the different uh
types of uh elements which are already
present in the table element type for
the row element okay so using this uh we
can uh basically find out what values
are present for any particular row and
we can buffer them we can verify them um
and then we can use it across different
test steps uh for our test case Okay so
this is how you can basically automate
your Dynamic web tables uh in your
application using tosa
that's all for this particular video if
you have any questions then please leave
it in the comments if you like this
video then please subscribe to our
Channel thanks for watching and I will
see you in the next
video